Sirius T. Bontea

Fort Leavenworth, Kansas
☐ 513.319.0522

<u>sirius.bontea@protonmail.com</u>

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/siriusbontea/

https://siriusbontea.github.io/

Project Management • Operations Planning • Process Improvement

Veteran whose calm demeanor thrives in high-stress, no-fail, resource-constrained environments. Extensive knowledge in project planning and ability to manage complex matrixed organizations to enable scaling, provide direction, and increase efficiency and growth. Experience working with C-Suite Executives, negotiation skills, and managing a broad range of defense analysts, scientists, and engineers. Develops project plans that allow for analyzing data, establishing schedules, optimizing workflow, driving decisions, and developing ideal solutions.

- Active DoD Top Secret w/ SCI security clearance
- Build processes to increase revenue margins
- Strategic planning design for direction and growth
- Perform operations analysis for budgeting to reduce cost
- Leading Executive crossfunctional teams
- Data-informed decisions and detailed planning
- Implement tools and improve systems
- Geospatial analysis and web development
- Increase communications to maintain standards

July 2020 - Present

Professional Experience

United States Army, Fort Leavenworth, KS Deputy Director of Continuous Improvement

Serving as the senior risk advisor in a world-class consulting organization that provides comprehensive organizational assessments for executive-level staffs.

- Trained a team of cross-functional advisors charged with coaching 22 Army executive-level organizations in risk analysis, risk mitigation, and process improvements.
- Designed and published new risk mitigation methods, adapted for large Army organizations, which were adopted by 3 organizations supporting ~30k personnel.
- Lead planning efforts for the Senior Director in support of COVID-19 health services operations, resulting in zero delays for ~250 personnel supporting multinational missions.

United States Army, Aberdeen Proving Ground, MD Director of Plans and Future Operations

July 2017 – July 2020

Served as the lead planner and coordinator for future operations, responsible for providing purpose and direction for a cross-functional staff of 30 employees that provided continuously updated technical analysis and time-sensitive products for 6 multinational organizations in Europe, Asia, and Africa.

- Hand-selected to represent the COO to provide technical subject matter expertise on operations and logistics affecting the movement of 3,800 personnel and special equipment distributed across 16 states into 3 Asian countries.
- Directed a specialized team of 17 analysts, scientists, and telecommunications specialists in providing scalable operations plans for hazard response, protection, and resourcing for ~180k personnel, ~70 large-scale facilities, and equipment across 9 European and 5 African countries.
- Represented the organization's CEO to develop concepts and lead planning efforts for hazard response operations which were incorporated and codified into Army-wide training and technical manuals used by military planners and senior leaders across the force.

Additional Skills

- **Business Administration Hubspot CRM, Teamwork CRM, Odoo CRM, Google Suite, Office365, Sharepoint Administration, Risk Assessment, Risk Mitigation, Occupational Safety
- **Data Analytics** Regression Analysis, Factor Analysis, SQL, Knowledge Management, Data Mining, Forecasting, Research, PostgreSQL and PostGIS for Geospatial Databases
- </> Programming Front end web development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript (Leaflet, Openlayers, Bootstrap, and D3 libraries), Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator for web graphics, Python scripting for Geospatial Information Systems, Visual Basic for Applications (VBA) for Office365 automation
- Geospatial Analysis Geospatial Information Systems (ArcGIS Pro, QGIS), Hazard Prediction

Other Professional Experience

EquipmentShare, Kansas City, KS *Military Intern*

September – November 2022

Served as consultant for process improvement, responsible for streamlining telematics operations.

- Mapped the logistics process and communications flow between warehouse operations and the
 customer. Identified performance gaps and provided recommended solutions to installation utilization
 and logistics processes to reduce waste, increase cost savings, and create shared understanding.
- Created data visualizations of the Returned Materials Authorization (RMA) process to identify performance shortfalls and provided the Senior Director with recommendations to improve efficiency.

United States Army, Fort Leonard Wood, MO Deputy Director of Training

January 2015 - June 2016

Served as the Deputy Director of Training supervising 7 direct reporting managers responsible for overseeing the training and development of over 4.8k personnel annually.

- Planned, resourced, supervised, and evaluated the company's systems, staff organization, synchronization and functions, and administration budget.
- Supervised 4 contracting and supply specialists for all company purchases and fund activities in excess of \$250k annually resulting in zero cost overruns.
- Supervised workforce management, facilities maintenance, and budget actions of over \$8M for facilities and equipment resulting in exemplary inspection ratings during annual budget audits.

United States Army, Fort Gordon, GA Senior Manager of Advanced Technical Training

August 2009 - December 2013

Served as Senior Manager supervising 18 direct reporting managers of a 420 personnel organization providing specialized technical training, facilities management, and process improvement.

- Selected above peers to lead and develop a team of managers responsible for high visibility operation under budget-constrained and time-sensitive conditions.
- Detailed planning, servant leadership, and negotiation skills enabled overwhelming success by completing an operation under budget and earlier than the required timeline. Exceeded the expectations of the CEO and earned praise and recognition for the entire team.

Research and Professional Writing

- America's Achilles Heel: Defense Against High-Altitude Electromagnetic Pulse–Policy vs. Practice. **Phttps://apps.dtic.mil/sti/citations/ADA613532**
- Cyber Threat to Military Just-In-Time Logistics: Risk Mitigation and the Return to Forward Basing.

 Phttps://apps.dtic.mil/sti/citations/AD1038872

Education & Certifications

- Graduate Certificate Digital Mapping University of Kentucky; 4.00 GPA
- Master's Degree (MMAS) Operations and Planning
 U.S. Army School of Advanced Military Studies (SAMS); 3.77 GPA
- Master's Degree (MMAS) Homeland Security Studies
 U.S. Army Command and General Staff College (CGSC); 3.60 GPA
- Bachelor's Degree (BS) Diplomacy and Military Studies Hawaii Pacific University; 3.49 GPA
- Signal Officer Advanced Course IT, Cyber Security, Network Management U.S. Army Cyber Center of Excellence
- Chemical Officer Basic Course Hazmat Operations, Inspections, Hazard Prediction U.S. Army Maneuver Support Center of Excellence
- Journeyman Meteorologist Forcasting, Observation, Data Collection and Analysis U.S. Air Force Weather Training Complex
- Physics Major

University of Hawaii at Hilo; completion through Junior year

▼ Honors & Awards

- 49th Annual Cartography and Geographic Information Society Map Design Competition Honorable Mention for the David Woodward Digital Map Award.
- Awarded the Bronze Star Medal for meritorious service in support of combat operations.